ANDERSON HOFF, PhD

Postdoctoral Researcher London, ON – Canada

Cell: +1 (437) 388-2440 | email: hoffande@gmail.com Personal site: www.andersonhoff.github.io

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a researcher in the field of chaos theory, time series and data analysis, with a solid background in Physics, Mathematics and Statistics. Moreover, I have an extensive laboratory and data analysis practice, carry good managerial skills and teach abilities. I am highly motivated to fulfill a position in research and/or data analysis, focusing on results to deliver excellence services and to impact people's life.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Exceptional ability in advanced research and analysis.
- Proficient in R and MS Office, with broad knowledge of other languages.
- Huge Physics, Mathematics and Statistics knowledge.
- Goal-oriented and excel to complete ongoing projects with outstanding results.
- Able to master new concepts and skills quickly and handle stressful circumstances.
- Teach and communicate to both specialist and non-specialist audiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher

2018 - 2019

Santa Catarina State University, Joinville, SC - Brazil

- Work on electronic chaotic circuit development and analysis, with experimental, theoretical and computational resources.
- Time series collection and characterization through Chaos Theory fundamentals.
- Developed new tools and routines for computational analysis of large datasets using R.
- Co-supervised Master and Graduating students.
- Collaborated with researchers to advance research and gain deeper understanding of chaotic systems behavior, with three publications in high-impact scientific journals.

Professor (part-time)

2018 - 2018

UniSociesc and Catholic University, Jaraguá do Sul, SC - Brazil

- Physics I Professor in Engineering classes.
- · Created new lessons plans based on course objectives.
- Provided on-line support for students in Math, Calculus I and II, Algebra, and Physics.

Research Assistant 2014 - 2017

Federal University of Parana, Curitiba, PR - Brazil

• Researched on development and characterization of thin-film solar cells, working with organic and inorganic materials.

- Helped with large survey research projects and provided research support for data processing operations.
- Planned, modified, and executed research techniques, procedures and tests, as AFM, XRD, SEM, impedance spectroscopy.
- Prepared materials for reports, presentations and submission to peer-reviewed journal publications.
- · Cleaned and maintained equipment in good working conditions.
- Four publications in high-impact scientific journals.

EDUCATION

Doctorate in Physics Federal University of Paraná, Curitiba, PR - Brazil	2014 – 2017
Master's in Physics Santa Catarina State University, Joinville, SC – Brazil	2012 – 2014
Bachelor's in Physics Santa Catarina State University, Joinville, SC – Brazil	2003 – 2007

LINKS

- Personal site: https://www.andersonhoff.github.io
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anderson-hoff-11582b23
- GitHub: https://github.com/AndersonHoff

PUBLICATIONS

9 scientific papers published in international peer-reviewed journals, as Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells, Physics Letters A, European Physical Journal B, Journal of Materials Science, International Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos. The complete list can be accessed in:

- Publons: https://publons.com/researcher/2942675/anderson-hoff/
- Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com.br/citations?user=oV62NPgAAAAJ&hl=en